Section A. Directions.
In this section, you will hear two long conversations.
At the end of each conversation, you will hear four questions.
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. Conversation 1.
can't believe my eyes, Bill.
Are you having a salad for lunch?
No hamburger? Get used to it, Susan.
I'm off burgers for good.
Most fast food is loaded with N.A., a kind of chemical substance.
I've been reading about a new healthy snack food.
It's made from fish.
Have you heard anything about it?
I haven't, but I don't like fish very much anyway.
But why are you interested in lessening your salt intake?
My doctor says I should cut back on N.A.
rich foods to lower my blood pressure.
Actually, my blood pressure isn't that high, but they say it increases with age.
I would've thought you were too young for that.
Well, I'm glad you're starting to pay more attention to your diet.
I've been eating lots of fruits and vegetables recently.
want to lower my risk of heart attack and stroke, too.
Recently, my family are trying to eat more healthy food.
So am I.
That's why I've been trying to lower my cholesterol levels.
Just like you, I'm now trying to lose a few pounds, too.
In that case, you should come to my health club with me.
Can you tear yourself away from the TV tonight?
You've joined a health club.
I would never have dreamed that you'd take something like this so seriously.
Why not? If you can break your unhealthy eating habits, I can surely break a sweat.
I can do a hundred push in a row.
Don't get jealous.
You will do it someday.
Questions 1 to 4 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 1. Which substance can be found in most fast food according to the man?
Question 2. Why does the man want to reduce salt in
Question 3. What problem does the woman have?
Question 4. What is a woman going to do from now on?
Conversation 2. Watches and clocks seem as much a part of our life as breathing or
eating. And yet, do you know the development of watches and clocks?
Joseph, nice to meet you.
Could you tell us something about watches and clocks?
Jennifer, nice to meet you, too.
Actually, watches and clocks were rare in the United States until the late 1850s.
In the late 1700s, people didn't know the exact time unless they were near a Those
delightful clocks in the squares of European towns were built for the public.
After all, at that time, most citizens simply couldn't afford a personal timepiece.
Well, until the 1800s in Europe and the United States, the main purpose of a watch,
which, by the way, was often on a gold chain, was to show others how wealthy you
were. Um, well, talking about watches, we have to one word, wristwatch, that makes
us realize the significance of on time.
The word wristwatch didn't even enter the English language until nearly 1900.
By then, the rapid pace of industrialization in the United States meant that
measuring time had become essential.
And since industrialization made possible the manufacture of large quantities of
goods, watches became fairly inexpensive.
Yes. Efficiency was now measured by how fast the job was done.
Being on time had entered the language and life of every citizen.
Um, recently, I've often thought that those who have left watches are likely to lose
their sensitivity to time.
Questions 5 to 8 are based on the conversation you have just heard.
Question 5. How did most Europeans know the exact time in the late 1700s?
Question 6. Why did the Europeans wear watches in the 1800s?
Question 7. What factor made wristwatches more affordable to citizens?
Question 8. What do the speakers mainly discuss?
Section B. Directions.
In this section, you will hear two passages.
At the end of each passage, you will hear three or four questions.
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. Passage 1.
Independence Day is the national holiday of the United States of America,
commemorating the signing of the Declaration of Independence by the Continental
Congress on July 4,
1776, in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
At the time of the signing, the U.S.
consisted of 13 colonies under the rule of England's King George III.
There was growing unrest in the colonies concerning the taxes that had to be to
England. This was commonly referred to as taxation without representation, as the
colonists did not have any representation in the English Parliament and had no say
in what went on.
As the unrest grew in the colonies,
King George sent extra troops to help control any rebellion.
In April 1775, as the King's troops advanced on Concord, Massachusetts, Paul Revere
would sound the alarm that the British are coming, the British are coming, as he
rode his horse through the late night streets.
The Battle of Concord and its shot herd round the world would mark the unofficial
beginning of the colonies' war for independence.
The following May, the colonies again sent delegates to the Second Continental
Congress. By June 1776, a committee was formed to compose a formal Declaration of
Independence. Thomas Jefferson was chosen to write the first draft, which was
presented to the Congress on June 28.
After various changes, a vote was taken late in the afternoon of July 4.
And although the signing of the Declaration was not completed until August, the
Fourth of July has been accepted as the official anniversary of the United States'
independence. Questions 9 to 11 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Question 9. Why were the colonists dissatisfied with England?
Question 10. When was the War of Independence declared unofficially?
Question 11. What can we learn about the Declaration of Independence?
Passage 2. Young women are losing faith in the university system, with nearly half
believing it is not worth getting a degree, tuition fees and little chance of
landing a good job make higher education an unattractive prospect for them.
study suggests it found that half of female graduates would not go to university if
they had the chance again.
The research will cause concern because it was carried out before the government
announced that fees will almost treble to £9,000 in 2014.
The findings have prompted warnings that a generation of ambitious young women will
miss out on a high -flying career and the opportunity to continue their education.
Louise Court, editor of Cosmopolitan magazine, which conducted the survey, said
young women seem to think of university as a waste of time.
It's never been harder to be a young woman with ambition, she said.
Understandably, women are angry and frustrated about their future, and this is
having a damaging effect on their self -esteem.
The survey of 1,353 women also looked at the career prospects and financial outlook
for women in 2014.
Two -thirds of those questions said they thought it would be almost impossible to
get their dream job, and a quarter were unable to follow their preferred career.
Only 14 said they felt safe from the sack.
Vicki Tuck said, The rise in fees is going to make a of people reflect on why they
are going to university.
I believe that women should only go to university if they have a genuine interest in
learning, a precious opportunity.
If they go purely to get a job, many will be disappointed.
Questions 12 to 15 are based on the passage you have just heard.
Why are most women losing faith in the university system?
What do the findings of the research warn us?
Question 14. What can we learn from Louise Court about young women under the current
university system?
Question 15. What was the attitude of most women surveyed towards their career
prospects? Section C.
Directions. In this section, you will hear three recordings of lectures or talks,
followed by three or four questions.
The recordings will be played only once.
After you hear a question, you must choose the best answer from the four choices
marked A, B, C, and D.
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet 1 with a single line through the
center. Recording 1.
Hello, ladies and gentlemen.
It gives me great pleasure to introduce our speaker for today's lecture, Dr.
Mike Donald. Dr.
Donald, professor of sociology at Washington University, has written numerous
articles and books on the issue of interpersonal relationships, which tend to be a
key factor to success in the modern society.
Thank you for that introduction.
I feel happy to meet you here.
From the moment you meet someone for the first time, you quickly want to assess who
the person is and what they represent.
That is why you may be on the lookout for certain stable qualities like honesty,
kindness, and intelligence.
Paying attention to these things may even help you evaluate if you will want to
pursue an intimate relationship with this person or not.
According to a study, way someone writes and the size of their handwriting can tell
you certain things about the person.
According to the research, which was conducted by the National Pen Company, it is
revealed that people with small handwriting tend to be shy, meticulous, and
studious, while people who are more outgoing tried gaining attention with larger
handwriting. Those who take things seriously put more pressure on the pen when they
write, while light -handed writers typically tend to be empathetic and more
sensitive. According to an article in Psychology Today, color you frequently turn to
for clothes or are more akin to says a lot about who you are.
People who frequently choose black are sensitive, artistic, and attentive to
details, while those who love red live life to the fullest and are proactive in
their endeavors. People who love green are loyal and affectionate, while those who
love white are organized and logical, and those who have blue as their favorite
color are stable, sensitive, and are considerate of others.
Certain body -focused repetitive behaviors can say a lot about your personality.
How your body reacts to situations, whether by pulling your hair, biting your nails,
or picking at your skin, could elicit impatience, frustration, boredom, and
dissatisfaction. Take nail -biting for example.
According to a research, is suggested that those who bite their nails tend to be
perfectionists, while also tense and often nervous.
According to psychologists, you can correctly judge a person just by looking at
their shoes. According to the lead researcher, Omri Galath from the University of
Kansas, just by examining the cost, style, color, and condition of the shoe, you can
be able to guess about 90 of the owner's personal characteristics, such as his or
her income, political affiliation, gender, and even age.
Hope you enjoyed today's lecture.
Thank you. Questions 16 to 19 are based on the recording you have just heard.
16. What does the introduction say about Dr.
Donald's articles and books?
Question 17. Which is the trait people with large handwriting have got?
Question 18. What do we know about people who love white?
Question 19. Which is the correct description for the people who bite their nails?
Recording 2. morning.
I feel honored to give you a speech today.
Enjoying the holiday season as a new family of is exciting, but if the scents,
sights, and sounds that you grew up with are nowhere to be found, you may be short
on holiday spirit.
Before going grinch on your spouse and loved ones, try these tips from other couples
who learned how to make the holidays together special.
First, be sentimental.
There's nothing like the holiday season to bring out your softer side, so this year,
embrace it. Every year on St.
Nicholas Day, my wife and I write each other letters with favorite memories and
hopes for the coming year, says Brianne Sanchez of Des Moines, Iowa.
We put them in each other's stockings and read them on Christmas.
It's time to reflect and, one day, to look back as the letters will remind us of
different stages of our marriage.
Second, think and act like a kid.
Channeling the wonder of a little one can turn the smallest of moments into a
memorable event. Follow the lead of Chadwick Boyd of Atlanta.
I hope Christmas with my friends and everyone who comes to dinner gets a homemade
felt stocking shaped like Rudolph or Santa Claus.
Opening the silly little stocking gifts turns adults into kids again.
I know my grandparents are happy that I'm carrying on their tradition.
Third, share experiences.
Pressure to purchase gifts, decorations, and even new clothes can distract from what
really matters. Charlene Breakey of New York City shares, have a Scandinavian advent
elf that has a pocket for every day of December.
I fill it each day with a note, such as a joke, a riddle, or a plan to go ice
skating that night.
It gets us thinking about being together as a family, not just shopping.
And fourth, get cooking.
In my family, holidays are all about the food.
For Christmas, there's panettone and pizzella.
For Easter, we tuck into ricotta pie.
But when I learned that my husband grew up enjoying Huckleberry cheesecake on his
birthday, I started baking one for him each year.
The payoff of delicious treats and the knowledge that I am helping to create new
memories for our family of is more than worth the effort.
Thanks for listening.
Goodbye. 20 to 22 are based on the recording you have just heard.
Question 20. What depresses newly married couples on holidays?
Question 21. Why do Brian Sanchez and his wife write letters to each other?
Question 22. What does the speaker say about shopping while traveling?
Recording 3. The Great Lakes is the greatest wonder of America.
It is the largest group of lakes in the world and the biggest body of freshwater.
It is hard to grasp that a land should contain several freshwater seas so big that a
ship can steam out of sight off the shore for a day or more or even sink in giant
waves. Lake Ontario is the smallest of the Great Lakes.
But compared with the others, Ontario is more elusive because of the Niagara Falls
and its sheer thunderous drop.
Lake Erie is the fourth largest lake by surface area of the five Great Lakes in
North America and the 13th largest globally if measured in terms of surface area.
It is the southernmost, shallowest, and smallest by volume of the Great Lakes and
therefore also has the shortest average water residence time.
Lake Huron is the second largest of the lakes.
It is shared on the east by the Canadian province of Ontario and on the west by the
state of Michigan in the United States.
The name of the lake is derived from early French explorers who named it for the
Huron people inhabiting the region.
The Huronian glaciation was named due to evidence collected from Lake Huron region.
Lake Michigan is the only one of the five Great Lakes of North America that is
located entirely within the United States.
Lake Michigan is shared from west to east by the US states of Wisconsin, Illinois,
Indiana, and Michigan.
The word Michigan originally referred to the lake itself and is believed to come
from the Ojibwa word michigami, meaning great water.
Our destination now is Superior, the largest freshwater lake in the world, also the
deepest one of the five Great Lakes.
If you stood on the moon, you could see the Great Lakes and recognize the familiar
wolf head shape of Lake Superior.
There is a graceful stillness on Lake Superior.
The rounded humped along the shores look like burial mounds of the gods.
Yet for all their size and power, the Great Lakes are fragile.
In the past, this fragile nature wasn't recognized and the lakes were mistreated for
economic gain, placing the ecosystem under tremendous stress from human activities.
Question 24. What does the word Michigan mean in Ojibwa language?
Question 25. What makes Lake Superior unique to the world?
This is end of comprehension.